Guide to the Elias Daniel Weigle Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Elias Daniel Weigle papers
1869-1938
MS 1195
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
17
(17 boxes)
The papers contain correspondence, sermons, notes, writings and memorabilia of Elias D. Weigle, minister of Trinity Lutheran Church in Mechanicsburg, Pennsylvania.
Weigle, Elias Daniel, 1848-1923
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Richard D. Weigle, 1976.
Scope and Contents
The papers contain correspondence, sermons, notes, writings and memorabilia of Elias D. Weigle, minister of Trinity Lutheran Church in Mechanicsburg, Pennsylvania.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Clergy; Families; Canada; Europe -- Description and travel; Sermons; Clergy; Weigle, Elias Daniel, 1848-1923; Weigle, Hanna Bream; Weigle, Luther A. (Luther Allan), 1880-1976; Trinity Lutheran Church (Mechanicsburg, Pa.)
- Inventory
  - Notes, writings, sermons, clippings, photographs, report cards, and printed materials, Circa 1875-1923 (Box 1–15)
- Additional Material, Circa 1869-1938; Accession 1977-M-004
  - Correspondence, 1907-1938
    - Elias D. Weigle to Hanna Bream Weigle (Mrs. E.D.) and children (letters from Luther Allen Weigle enclosed), 25 ALS, 1907 June 21-August 27 (Box 1)
    - Hanna Bream Weigle to E.D. and L.A. Weigle (letters from children enclosed), 14 ALS, 1 TLS, clippings, receipts, 1907 June 22-September 1 (Box 1)
    - Luther A. Weigle to Mr. [illegible] and Mrs. E.D. Weigle, 12 TLS, 4 ALS, 2 TD, 2 TL, 1923 August 23-[illegible], 1938 May 23 (Box 1)
    - Luther A. Weigle to Harriet Weigle Nicely, TLS, 1923 December 13 (Box 1)
    - Clara Boxrud Weigle (Mrs. L.A.) to Mr. and Mrs. E.D. Weigle, 4 ALS, 1907 December 14-1938 April 9, undated (Box 1)
    - George W. and Harriet Weigle Nicely to E.D. and L.A. Weigle, 3 ALS, 1907 June 23-August 9 (Box 1)
    - George W. and Harriet Weigle Nicely to Mrs. E.D. Weigle and Dan Weigle, 4 ALS, 1 ALS fragment, 1907 July 22-1935 January 20? (Box 1)
    - Daniel Weigle to E.D and L.A. Weigle, 2 ALS, 1907 July 2-11 (Box 1)
    - Richard D. Weigle to Mrs. E.D. Weigle, 3 TLS, 1935 February 5-1938 May 28 (Box 1)
    - Richard D. Weigle to Harriet Weigle Nicely, 1 TLS, 1938 May 23 (Box 1)
    - Non-family correspondence to E.D. Weigle and Mrs. Hanna Bream Weigle, 2 TLS, 6 ALS, 1 TD, 1 TDS, 1922 August 31-1938 May 30 (Box 1)
  - Sermons, notes, class notes, writings, 1874-1919?
    - AL notecards (Box 1)
    - Sermons written on verso of miscellaneous papers, envelopes, and ALS (Box 1)
    - Clippings (Box 1)
    - "History of Ten Years of Trinity Lutheran Church at Camp Hill", 1908 September 11 (Box 1)
    - Travel journals with clippings enclosed (Box 1)
      - 1907 Jul 7-15, 29-? (Box 1)
      - 1907 Aug 17 - Sep 6 (Box 1)
      - 1907 Sep 6 - 0ct ? (Box 1)
      - 1907 Aug 3-21 (Box 1)
    - 9 clippings of articles written by E.D. Weigle to the Mechanicsburg, PA newspaper regarding his trip abroad, 1907 July 13-August 12 (Box 1)
  - Diaries, ledgers, day journals, pronouncing gazette, 1869-1923 (Box 2)
  - Lutheran church pamphlets, subscription record, memorabilia (includes synod proceedings, biblical quotation cards, program cards announcing E.D. Weigle's trip, abroad), 1895-1923, undated (Box 2)
  - Classbook, history books, guidebook, dictionary, 1867-1937 (Box 2)
  - Daniel Elias Weigle sermon, 1915 May 9 (Box 2)
  - Unidentified writing, "The Culprit Fay" (signed Dane), undated (Box 2)
  - Memorabilia, 1869-1912?
    - License to preach, 1877 September 23 (Box 2)
    - Certificate of ordination, 1878 September 15 (Box 2)
    - Wedding invitation to L.A. Weigle and Clara Boxrud wedding, 1909 June 15 (Box 2)
    - "Golden Wedding Memorial" for Hanna Bream Weigle's parents, Circa 1890? (Box 2)
    - Passenger list for S.S. Canada with E.D. and L.A. Weigle listed, 1907 August 29 (Box 2)
    - 1 drawer pull (Box 2)
    - Set of skeleton keys (Box 2)
    - Shipping tag (Box 2)
    - Photo album, 1868-1889? (Box 2)
    - Calender, 1912 (Box 2)